<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>算法 on Zachary's Blog</title><link>https://jiacs.com/tags/%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95/</link><description>Recent content in 算法 on Zachary's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jiacs.com/tags/%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Peterson算法中turn(will_wait)变量的作用</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/peterson-algo-turn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/peterson-algo-turn/</guid><description>&lt;p>最近在操作系统上学习了Peterson算法，其使用了3个变量就实现了纯软件的线程同步，即两个线程的标记变量&lt;code>c1&lt;/code>, &lt;code>c2&lt;/code>以及一个&lt;code>turn&lt;/code>变量。
但是对于其为什么要使用第三个变量还不是很了解，今天特意研究了一下，终于发现了第三个变量的作用。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT 1052 Linked List Sorting (25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1052/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1052/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A linked list consists of a series of structures, which are not necessarily adjacent in memory. We assume that each structure contains an integer key and a Next pointer to the next structure. Now given a linked list, you are supposed to sort the structures according to their key values in increasing order.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT 1051 Pop Sequence (25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1051/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1051/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Given a stack which can keep M numbers at most. Push N numbers in the order of 1, 2, 3, &amp;hellip;, N and pop randomly. You are supposed to tell if a given sequence of numbers is a possible pop sequence of the stack. For example, if M is 5 and N is 7, we can obtain 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 from the stack, but not 3, 2, 1, 7, 5, 6, 4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT-1047 Student List for Course (25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1047/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1047/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Zhejiang University has 40000 students and provides 2500 courses. Now given the registered course list of each student, you are supposed to output the student name lists of all the courses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT 1033 To Fill or Not to Fill (25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1033/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1033/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With highways available, driving a car from Hangzhou to any other city is easy. But since the tank capacity of a car is limited, we have to find gas stations on the way from time to time. Different gas station may give different price. You are asked to carefully design the cheapest route to go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT 1048 Find Coins (25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1048/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1048/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eva loves to collect coins from all over the universe, including some other planets like Mars. One day she visited a universal shopping mall which could accept all kinds of coins as payments. However, there was a special requirement of the payment: for each bill, she could only use exactly two coins to pay the exact amount. Since she has as many as 105 coins with her, she definitely needs your help. You are supposed to tell her, for any given amount of money, whether or not she can find two coins to pay for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PAT 1039 Course List for Student(25)</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1039/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/pat-1039/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="题目要求">题目要求&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Zhejiang University has 40000 students and provides 2500 courses. Now given the student name lists of all the courses, you are supposed to output the registered course list for each student who comes for a query.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Floyd判圈算法（龟兔赛跑算法）</title><link>https://jiacs.com/p/floyd-algo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jiacs.com/p/floyd-algo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="问题">问题：&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>如何判断一个链表是否有闭环？&lt;/p>
&lt;p>今天看到了这个问题，提到了Floyd判圈算法，于是去查了一下这个算法，把自己的一点想法写下来。&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>